# S.M TALHA

## **Electrical Engineer**

Karachi, Pakistan

0303-2188645, 0333-2380757

s.mtalha1992@gmail.com,



Electrical Engineer having specialization in Control & Automation, Expert in System Maintenance & trouble shooting with a strong learning & experience in Textile & Packaging sector in the Maintenance department, Now ready to Further grow my skill sets along with exposure in upward and onwards knowledge under a dynamic working environment.

### **EXPERIENCE:**

## **GULAHMED TEXTILE MILLS LTD.**

|Maintenance officer|

- Deputed as Maintenance Engineer in the finishing Department having Stenters, Sanforize, Grey Pilling &
- Export Folding Machines.
- Involved in the project of ECOSTAR mixed nozzle gas burners GRM 30 series.
- Involved in Programming(PLC: Siemens-S7300, Language: ladder-Logic) of Shrinkage Monitoring System installed at Sanforizing Machine.
- To maintain all Stenters of Bruckner & Tung Yang by means of their selvedge uncurler, EL guider for chain, proximity sensors, circulation motors and stenter area of burners for all left & right section.
- Troubleshoot VFD's, Inverters and PLC's.
- Hands on working on Oracle Inventory Management System & Well versed on reading Electrical Diagrams.

#### 2017-2021

March

2021-2023

## M&F Commercial Corporation (Pvt.) Ltd.

|Assistant Engineer Leading to Maintenance Engineer|

- Lead and carry out complete Predictive and preventive maintenance of Printing, Lamination & Slitting
- Machines along with documents control measures.
- Involved in the Development and Implementation of preventive maintenance programs at the floor. Report operational & functional issues to Manager and plans out remedial action accordingly.
- Assign breakdown maintenance complaints to respective Electrical and Mechanical teams.
- Prepare Purchase/Repair documents for Machines parts, Ensure timely sourcing and as per standards.
- Allocate work and completion in accordance with the Monitoring system (CMMS).
- Familiarized with ISO 9001, ISO 14001 and ISO 45001, Thereby, Ensure rectification of different suitable & complex findings related to Audits and EHS.
- Provided an element of cost, program, safety and build ability advice on proposed maintenance.
- Lead and Support continuous improvements initiatives through a wide range of upgrades to assets qualitatively.

#### **EDUCATION:**

### 2018-2020

# 2011-2015

#### M.S ELECTRICAL (CONTROL & AUTOMATION)

Bahria University, Karachi.

## **B.E ELECTRICAL (ELECTRONICS)**

Hamdard University, Karachi.

## **TRAININGS:**

- Health, Safety and Environment (In-house)
- Emergency handling and ESD Systems
- Social Compliance (In-house)